{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Cholesterol is somewhat amphipathic due to", "opta": "the single hydroxyl along with the hydrocarbon nature of the remainder of the molecule", "optb": "the long branched hydrocarbon along with the four hydrocarbon rings", "optc": "the five-methyl groups along with the hydrocarbon chain", "optd": "the three six-membered rings along with the single five-membered ring", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacteriorhodopsin", "opta": "absorbs light and pumps protons", "optb": "is an integral membrane protein", "optc": "contains primarily alpha-helical residues", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In active transport, the membrane structure that functions is", "opta": "cholesterol", "optb": "integral proteins", "optc": "carbohydrates", "optd": "hydrophobic molecules", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cholesterol is essential for normal membrane functions because it", "opta": "plugs up the cardiac arteries of older men", "optb": "cannot be made by higher organisms", "optc": "keeps membranes fluid.", "optd": "spans the thickness of the bilayer", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The model that is now known to be correct for the structure of biological membrane is", "opta": "Fluid mosaic model", "optb": "Page's model", "optc": "Lac Operon model", "optd": "Lock and Key model", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In Fluid mosaic model, the biological membrane can be viewed as", "opta": "two dimensional solutions of oriented lipids and globular proteins", "optb": "three dimensional solutions of oriented lipids and globular proteins", "optc": "two dimensional solutions of oriented lipids and carbohydrate", "optd": "three dimensional solutions of oriented lipids and carbohydrate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Membrane lipids are", "opta": "hydrophilic", "optb": "hydrophobic", "optc": "ampiphillic", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pinocytosis occurs in", "opta": "all eukaryotic cells", "optb": "all prokaryotic cells", "optc": "mitochondria of all cells", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Exocytosis is the secretion of proteins", "opta": "out of the cell across the plasma membrane into the extracellular space", "optb": "out of the cell across the plasma membrane into the intracellular space", "optc": "is the uptake of macromolecules from the extracellular space into the cell across the plasma membrane", "optd": "is the uptake of macromolecules from the intracellular space into the cell across the plasma membrane", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The membrane proteins that catalyze active transport reactions differ from soluble enzymes as", "opta": "they are permanently changed during the reaction", "optb": "the substrates of the reaction are all outside the cell", "optc": "they do not enhance the rates of reaction", "optd": "the products of the reaction move in a specific direction", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The movement of molecules across a membrane by passive transport does not require", "opta": "an input of metabolic energy", "optb": "internal energy", "optc": "vibrational energy", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Peptidoglycan is a complex consisting of", "opta": "oligo-saccharide and protein", "optb": "polysaccharide and protein", "optc": "mono-saccharide and protein", "optd": "aminoacid and carbohydrate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mesosomes may be the sites of", "opta": "DNA replication and specialized enzymatic reactions", "optb": "RNA replications and specialized enzymatic reactions", "optc": "RNA replications and specialized cyclic reactions", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "Peroxisomes have a single boundary membrane", "optb": "Peroxisomes contain enzymes that degrade fatty acids and amino acids", "optc": "The byproduct of given reactions in (b) is toxic to cells", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The smooth endoplasmic reticulum (SER) is the site of", "opta": "phospholipid synthesis", "optb": "amino acid synthesis", "optc": "carbohydrate synthesis", "optd": "protein synthesis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysozymes are found in", "opta": "plant cells", "optb": "animal cells", "optc": "microbial cells", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Biological membranes are like water beds because", "opta": "they are always moving", "optb": "they (normally) do not leak their contents", "optc": "the membrane is thin compared to the enclosed volume", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The plasma membrane is a selectively permeable barrier due to presence of specific transport", "opta": "proteins", "optb": "amino acids", "optc": "carbohydrates", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of molecule spans the membrane, from its inner to outer surface according to the Fluid mosaic model of cell membranes?", "opta": "Cholesterol", "optb": "Phospholipid", "optc": "Protein", "optd": "Carbohydrate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "Membranes form boundaries around the cell and distinct subcellular components", "optb": "Membranes act as selectively permeable barrier", "optc": "Membranes contain varying amount of lipid and protein and some contain small amount of carbohydrates", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In membranes, lipids are", "opta": "glycerophospholipids", "optb": "sphingolipids", "optc": "sterols", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not found in membranes?", "opta": "Glycoproteins", "optb": "Glycolipids", "optc": "Nucleic acids", "optd": "Phospholipids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}